### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/vijendral (LinkedIn) lebakatech.com (Company)

Top Skills

CRM

**ERP** 

**Business Process** 

Languages

**English** 

Hindi

Telugu

Certifications

ВМС

# Vijendra Lebaka

Founder & CEO at LEBAKA TECHNOLOGIES

Greater Visakhapatnam Area

## Summary

Strategic, Results- Driven and multifaceted Manager with diverse experience across several industries, countries and domains. Focused on delivering complex, scalable and cost effective solutions for the respective Organizations. Forward-thinking, MBA -educated catalyst for Change. Talent for innovating within constraints and motivating teams. Exceptional communication and presentation skills. Equally effective in B2C and B2B Environments.

Specialties: CUSTOMER LOYALTY, BUSINESS ANALYTICS, DATA MODELLING, MARKET RESEARCH, COMPETITIVE ANALYSIS, ERP, Campaign Management, GTM & RTC Strategies, Loyalty Management, Corporate Communications, Branding and Identity

## Experience

LEBAKA TECHNOLOGIES
Founder & CEO
May 2019 - Present (1 year 4 months)
VISAKHAPATNAM, INDIA

Conceptualized with the notion that technology plays a major role in the day to day life of people, our goal and priority is to put ourselves in the customer's shoes, have an eye for detail and design products that will ideally cater to larger society. Whether you are building models or consuming data, our products are designed and delivered to be owned and managed by business users. Customer centric and user friendly, the ease with which our products can be used not only saves your valuable time but also gives value for money. With Lebaka Technologies, establishments catering to various businesses and of all sizes can plan smarter, report faster, and analyse better – transforming business performance in ways never imagined befor

CS Group Head Of Marketing September 2014 - April 2019 (4 years 8 months)

- # Responsible for end to end Marketing (Offline & Digital) Strategies.
- # Provide strategic direction and manage Business partner relationships.
- # Managing a team of 20-25 members driving them towards achieve organizational goals.
- # Developing metrics/dashboards to monitor market trends and company performance. Utilizing customer data to support marketing programs.
- # Drive strategic marketing communication initiatives for CS Group in advertising and corporate communication
- # Develop and monitor budgets to ensure revenue and expenses are kept within established boundaries.

#### **VEPL**

Manager CRM

June 2011 - September 2014 (3 years 4 months)

Visakhapatnam

- # Involved in creation, designing and implementing Multi-tier Loyalty Programs for target customers through analytical techniques (Customer Segmentation using Cluster Analysis) using SAS tool.
- # Monitoring customer centric year-long campaigns using data analytics, which leads to an average of 60% increase in sales and 40% increase in footfalls.
- # Generated reports to provide business insights which used to help in redefining the campaign target strategies.
- # Proficient in evaluating market & customer trends, and estimating TAM (Total Addressable Market) through business analytical technique like Time Series models.
- # Develop & Execute brand initiatives (ATL / BTL) customized by region, channel or key customers.
- # Developing metrics/dashboards to monitor market trends and company performance. Utilizing customer data to support marketing programs.
- # Working on Strategizing Customer Loyalty Program. Extensively worked in Internet/Online Marketing, Database Management and email lead generation.
- # Created and launched innovative retail promotions, co-promotions, corporate tie-ups, marketing collateral, advertising efforts and media relations.
- # Involved in the ecommerce and corporate website design, deployment and maintenance by coordinating with the team to ensure proper flow of the operations.
- # Executing New Product Development projects like GTM & RTC strategies.
- By participating in cross functional teams basis consumer insights.
- # Provide strategic direction and manage Business partner relationships.

# Managing a team of 20-25 members driving them towards achieve organizational goals.

#### Accenture

Sr. Business Consultant April 2011 - June 2011 (3 months)

# Providing comprehensive business requirements documents with complete front-end analysis to ensure the solution will meet the customer's business need.

# Gathering and documenting business requirements definition including gap analysis and scope definition, modeling (business and data), analysis (processes and controls), and all levels of written communication # Developing metrics/dashboards/reports to monitor market trends and company performance, Calculating the derivation of Potential by project type/customer type.

#### Meridian Partners

Sr. Business Consultant November 2009 - March 2011 (1 year 5 months) Miami

- # Collecting & analyzing data from various departments to provide valuable reports.
- # Business process mapping and reengineering. Prepares solution options, risk identification, and financial analyses such as cost/benefit, ROI, buy/build, etc.
- # Business Processes within support areas as they relate to existing or proposed systems and applications; suggesting improvements where appropriate.
- # Involved in functional and technical workshops with client to understand functional and data requirements of client markets and prepared data models to migrate data from legacy systems to new application (SAP).
- # Created a data model for clients using SAP BI Systems which would serve as single source of information for reporting purpose. This data model would improve the efficiency and would reduce the adhoc reports requested by business users
- # Ensured data loads as per plan for both UAT & production environment # Work with IT and business project teams to understand reporting and ERP requirements and propose solutions.

#### Sescoi International

**ERP Sales Manager** 

October 2007 - August 2009 (1 year 11 months)

Pune

# Identified new customers for Sescoi's applications products (MyWorkPlan) in India.

# Worked with the business to prepare business cases, including cost benefit analysis.

# Developed and executed effective campaigns in reaching top-level executives and line-of-business (LOB) managers. Coordinating with the subject matter experts to better understand Sescoi Solutions and position the same in the target industry.

Accelon Technologies P Limited Sr. Exe Business Development June 2005 - September 2007 (2 years 4 months) Pune

# Analyzed medium sized to complex business issues and opportunities, working closely with internal business customers. Prospecting for new customers either by cold calling or web registrations.

# Performing inside sales from account profiling to account qualification in order to complete 30% of the product sales cycle and transitioning an account to the direct sales.

# Coordinating with pre-sales for presentations and demos & providing relevant customer inputs for the same.

The Coca-Cola Company
Marketing Executive
October 2000 - September 2003 (3 years)
Visakhapatnam

# To make critical estimation of the market potential, evaluation and screening of potential distributors and retailers and to develop a comprehensive strategy with a systematic approach to increase market share of the company.

# Managing large amounts of data for Sales analysis that could identify the key areas of growth to meet the objective.

# Managing and extracting data from various systems and applications for sales analysis.

## Education

Indian School of Business

Data Science, Business Analytics · (2016 - 2017)

International Institute of Information Technology, Pune Infotech Park, Hinjawadi, Pune 411057
MBA, IT · (2003 - 2005)

Andhra University

BE, Mechanical Engineering · (1996 - 2000)

Bloomberg

Bloomberg Market Concepts · (2017)

Shaw Academy

Diploma in Digital Marketing · (2017)